NATHAN (NATER) JORDE

(C) 612-423-5239 nater@iamnater.com https://github.com/natergj https://www.iamnater.com

PROFILE

Experienced full stack software developer with recent focus on React and GraphQL. Previously focused on Node.js system architecture with concentration on OS integration, data flow, API design & implementation and report generation. Strong proponent and contributor to open source software.

EXPERIENCE

CONTRACTOR HYDRATE LLC

AUG 2019-JAN 2020

- Supported teams and individuals needing up-skilling & re-skilling in software development
- Developed and delivered hands-on software development training sessions to groups with attendees ranging from those with no prior software development experience to senior developers. Topics included JavaScript, React.js, Git, Docker, functional programming, and more.
- Provided instruction to software development teams when implementing specific features in technologies unfamiliar to the team.

SENIOR ENGINEER HYDRATE LLC

SEP 2018-JUN 2019

- Contributed to project based work focusing mainly on React and GraphQL
- · Mentored and instructed junior developers
- Created GraphQL API server tutorial and accompanying project files which demonstrate the implementation of non-trivial features. https://github.com/hydrateio/advanced-graphql-server-tutorial

SENIOR WEB ENGINEER CODE42

SEP 2016-SEP 2018

- Worked on implementing new products and features using React/Redux frameworks
 Instrumental in quarties and leading a "I'Walk Infrastructural" to any that woulded along the street of the str
- Instrumental in creating and leading a "Web Infrastructure" team that worked closely
 with our User Experience designers to provide tooling and workflows useable by
 development teams when working on new product features
- Collaborated with cloud ops team to modernize web app deployment using Docker, Concourse and AWS deployments

SENIOR DEVELOPER HARVARD UNIVERSITY IT

APR 2016-AUG 2016

- Worked with University Cloud Ops team to deploy custom written financial management application into the Amazon Cloud.
- Continued development of financial management application's RESTful APIs and reports generation

INTEGRATED WEB SYSTEMS ARCHITECT

APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER

APPLICATIONS ANALYST

SCHOOL OF ENGINEERING AND APPLIED SCIENCES, HARVARD UNIVERSITY

MAR 2014-APR 2016

MAY 2013-MAR 2014

FEB 2012-MAY 2013

- Evaluated, deployed and supported administrative applications including the school's Apache web hosting infrastructure, Microsoft SharePoint, Tableau and other off-the-shelf software.
- Maintained the school's data services and infrastructure including a mix of Oracle, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL and MongoDB databases.
- Developed, deployed and maintained school's data ETL processes using Microsoft SSIS.
- Developed and deployed small scale database applications for student innovation resources and faculty committee assignments.
- In Fall 2012 took over management of failing project using a 3rd party software consultancy firm to develop a real-time web application to provide financial reporting for the school's researchers. After 9 months of delays, ended the partnership with the firm and rewrote nearly all of the codebase to implement a working version in 3 months. Following continued development and successful pilots at the Harvard School of Public Heath and the Harvard Medical School, this application is now being expanded for university-wide implementation in Spring/Summer 2016.
- From Spring 2014 led the small development group developing, maintaining and enhancing the administrative applications including research finance management, school course planning, faculty committee assignments, scientific instrumentation machining shop billing, employee on boarding and automated workflows.
- Applications were primarily written in Javascript using the MEAN stack, however full portfolio included applications written in C#, Ruby on Rails, PHP and Python.

GENIUS – APPLE COMPUTER MAC SPECIALIST – APPLE COMPUTER

DEC 2004-FEB 2012 JUNE 2004-DEC 2004

- As a Mac Specialist, used my knowledge of Apple Computers to find appropriate sales solutions for customers.
- As a Genius provided technical support to the general public on everything that Apple Inc would release. This included general information as well as troubleshooting and repair of failed hardware. This position was very team oriented for the successful support of the general public.
- In the seven and a half years that I had been with Apple Retail I had been stationed at five different stores in 4 different states. At each of the stores where I have been stationed I have implemented a Mac OS X Server solution for that store's employees to share files, have networked home directories and also many home grown web applications. I also set up shell scripts and AppleScripts for automation of tasks performed on routine basis for both maintenance and time saving tasks.

EDUCATION U

UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA

Minneapolis, MN — B.A. Studies in Cinema and Media Culture, 2004

EXPERIENCE

Seven years experience in web design/development Eight years experience in technical support

AWARDS

2014 - Venkatesh "Venky" Narayanamurti Award for Mentoring and Community Building - School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Harvard University

2015 - Harvard Hero - Harvard University

SKILLS

Mac OS X, CentOS, Apache, IIS, MS SQL Server, MySQL, Oracle, HTML, CSS, Google Apps Script, Javascript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, GraphQL, AngularJS,

MongoDB, Docker, DevOps, AWS, C#, PHP, Perl, Bash Shell Scripting, Agile, Jira, BitBucket, GIT, Confluence